Matthew Owen

matthew.owen95@gmail.com | +44 775 321 9340 | @_mattowen | github.com/matthewowen

Summary

I love the web, and I especially love it when the web makes painful 'real life' transactions easier. I've got great web project management and account management experience, and I can back it up with experience building products independently from the ground-up. I like to learn – I taught myself to program, and I'm currently taking Coursera courses on Functional Programming and Machine Learning.

Education

University of Oxford, BA (Hons) Classics and English

2006 - 2010

Study of Latin, Greek and English literature, philosophy, history, and language. The particular rigours of the Oxford arts system (loosely structured study focused around semi-weekly essays and one-on-one tutorials with senior faculty) instil a good capacity for self-direction, independent learning, and assertiveness on paper and in person. Graduated with a 2:1 – the UK and US university grading systems don't map that well, but this is roughly equivalent to a 3.5 – 3.7 GPA.

Wath-upon-Dearne Comprehensive School

1999 - 2006

Graduated with A-levels (roughly equivalent to AP classes) in Mathematics, Physics, and English Literature, all at grade A.

Professional Experience

Project Manager, Torchbox (Oxford, UK)

July 2010 - Present

Managing web development projects for major charities, NGOs and corporations. I've personally managed projects for clients including WWF, Yahoo!, Samsung, Oxfam, and ONE.

As well as general project and account management, my role means getting involved with the big picture of digital strategy and project definition and the nitty-gritty of functional specifications, wireframes, and use testing. When needed, I get my hands dirty with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python.

Intern, Oxford Technology Ventures (New York City, USA)

June 2009 - September 2009

As part of the development of a new web product, carried out market research and competitor analysis, and helped design the site workflows and user experience.

Sadly, the product didn't make it to market. I learnt a lot about what you should and shouldn't do.

Selected personal projects

SFTransit, OxBus

www.sftransit.us | www.oxbus.co.uk

Taking public transit is great. Waiting for it to arrive isn't. I've built a few apps designed to make the experience of taking public transit better, building each time on what I've learnt before.

I designed and built these from the ground up (consuming APIs where available, scraping consumer websites where they weren't) to make something better than the current options. To build them, I taught myself Python, Flask, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, redis, nginx, server administration (and more).